HBO原创连续剧
衣柜字幕组翻译制作
而这就是您最担心的？
And that's your biggest worry?
是的 任何一种病毒 但最担心的还是类似流感那种
Yes, any kind of virus, but most probably something similar to influenza.
因为会在空中传播
Because of air travel.
透过空气传播
Through the air.
- 咳嗽——  - 不好意思
-Coughing-- -I'm sorry.
我指的是飞机上的乘客
I meant people. On planes.
您在您的书里提到过这个
That was something you described in your book.
对 比方说 马达加斯加出现新病毒
Yes, a new virus in Madagascar, say,
也许几周内就会传播到芝加哥
could be in Chicago within a matter of weeks.
最终结果就是全球性流行病  “全”意味着“所有人”
And we end up with a global pandemic. Pan meaning "all."
全世界人口同时感染
The whole world becomes sick all at once.
纽曼博士 您也是一位流行病学专家
And, Dr. Neuman, you're also an epidemiologist.
我猜流行性病毒传播的可能也会让您夜不能寐
I presume the prospect of a viral pandemic keeps you up at night as well.
- 不会 - 不会？
-No. -No?
- 不会 - 好吧 那今天的节目就结束了
-No. -All right, well, that's our show.
不会 人类自古以来就跟病毒作斗争
No, mankind has been at war with the virus from the start.
有时候 如同战争一样 会有上百万人死去
Sometimes, millions of people die, as in an actual war.
但最后 我们总会胜利
But in the end, we always win.
但您——我没理解错的话 您确实认为微生物会造成威胁
But you-- just to be clear, you do think microorganisms pose a threat.
惨绝人寰的威胁
In the most dire terms.
- 细菌 - 不对
-Bacteria. -No.
- 您喜欢说不 - 是
-You like saying no. -Yes.
不是细菌 不是病毒
Not bacteria. Not viruses.
那是？
So?
真菌
Fungus.
对 一般都是这样的反应
Yes, that's the usual response.
真菌看似无害
Fungi seem harmless enough.
很多物种却深知其害
Many species know otherwise.
因为有些真菌的目的不是杀戮
Because there are some fungi who seek not to kill,
而是控制
but to control.
我问问你 我们的LSD是哪来的？
Let me ask you, where do we get LSD from?
LSD：麦角酸二乙酰胺，一种常见的致幻剂和精神兴奋剂
您是从哪儿弄来的？
Where do you get it from?
提取自麦角 是一种真菌
It comes from ergot, a fungus.
致幻蘑菇？也是真菌
Psilocybin? Also a fungus.
病毒会让我们生病 真菌却能改变我们的思维
Viruses can make us ill, but fungi can alter our very minds.
有种真菌能影响昆虫
There's a fungus that infects insects.
比方说 它进到一只蚂蚁体内
Gets inside an ant, for example,
通过循环系统传播至蚂蚁脑内
travels through its circulatory system to the ant's brain,
并用致幻剂灌满蚂蚁的大脑
and then floods it with hallucinogens,
就此使蚂蚁屈服于它的意志
thus bending the ant's mind to its will.
真菌开始主导这只蚂蚁的行为
The fungus starts to direct the ant's behavior,
告诉它要往哪走 该做什么
telling it where to go, what to do,
如同木偶师操纵傀儡
like a puppeteer with a marionette.
还不止如此
And it gets worse.
真菌需要食物来存活
The fungus needs food to live,
所以它开始从内部侵食它的宿主
so it begins to devour its host from within,
用自身来代替蚂蚁的血肉
replacing the ant's flesh with its own,
但它不会任由宿主死去
but it doesn't let its victim die.
不 它会防止这具傀儡腐化以确保其存活
No, it keeps its puppet alive by preventing decomposition.
怎么做到的？我们的青霉素是哪来的？
How? Where do we get penicillin from?
真菌
Fungus.
肖恩海斯博士 您好像有话要说
Dr. Schoenheiss, you're in distress.
这种真菌感染确实存在 但不会侵染人类
Fungal infection of this kind is real, but not in humans.
没错 如果宿主体温高于34.4度
True, fungi cannot survive if its host's internal temperature
那么真菌是无法存活的
is over 94 degrees.
目前而言 真菌没有理由进化
And currently, there are no reasons for fungi to evolve
来抵御更高的温度
to be able to withstand higher temperatures.
但如果这点改变了呢？
But what if that were to change?
如果 打个比方
What if, for instance,
这个世界变暖了一点呢？
the world were to get slightly warmer?
那现在 就有理由去进化了
Well, now there is reason to evolve.
只要一个基因突变 子囊菌 念珠菌 麦角菌
One gene mutates and an ascomycete, candida, ergot,
虫草菌 曲霉菌 其中任意一种便都可能
cordyceps, aspergillus, any one of them could become
有能力钻进我们的脑子里
capable of burrowing into our brains
继而控制不止百万 而是上亿人
and taking control not of millions of us, but billions of us.
数十亿个思维被毒害的傀儡
Billions of puppets with poisoned minds
永久执着于同一个目标：
permanently fixed on one unifying goal:
将真菌传播至每一个活人身上
to spread the infection to every last human alive
不惜一切手段
by any means necessary.
而且也不会有治疗手段
And there are no treatments for this.
没有预防药 没有特效药
No preventatives, no cures.
统统不存在 连研发出来都不可能
They don't exist. It's not even possible to make them.
要真发生了呢？
So, if that happens?
我们会输
We lose.
我们一会儿回来
We'll be back.
翻译  疾火＆叽拇啾
校对＆后期＆监制 北落
闹钟响了
Alarm.
闹钟响了！
Alarm!
松饼粉呢？
Where's the pancake mix?
噢 我该——
Oh, was I--
是该我买的 抱歉
Yeah, I was. Sorry.
我本来要给你做生日松饼的
I was gonna make you birthday pancakes.
这倒好
I swear.
我其实不喜欢松饼
You know I don't really like pancakes.
我知道你不喜欢 是我想吃
I know you don't like them. It was for my benefit.
补点维生素C
Vitamin C.
你作业做完了？
You get your homework done?
学到分数了？
Fractions?
你是多老了？
How old are you again?
36了
Thirty-six.
很快就该穿尿布了
Gonna have to wear diapers soon.
谁说我现在没穿？
Who says I don't already?
有蛋壳
Shell.
补点钙
Calcium.
真不错
Lovely.
有给汤米叔叔留吃的吗？
Is there enough for Uncle Tommy?
本来该有的
Well, there would've been.
你还活着呢 老不死的
You're still alive, you old fucker.
呦 他多爱你啊
Aw. He loves you.
这叫依赖我 不是一码事
He's dependent on me. Not the same.
- 我觉得是一码事 - 就是一码事
-I think it's the same. -It's definitely the same.
我还以为咱要吃松饼呢
I thought we was havin' pancakes.
我们在路上给你找点吃的
We'll pick you somethin' up on the road.
弄混凝土的会来吗？
Concrete guys gonna be there?
他们说也许会来
Yeah, they said maybe.
也许？不浇混凝土我们就没法定框架结构
Maybe? We can't frame until we pour.
不定框架结构我们就没有钱拿
We're not gettin' paid until we frame.
咱可以叫上别人
Well, we could bring someone else on,
- 干起活来也快些 - 不 不
-get the job done faster. -No, no.
我不会把活儿分出去
I'm not splittin' this job.
我都不想分给你
I barely wanna split it with you.
我们可以干两班
We could work a double.
认真的？非得在今天？
Literally? Today?
我有数 九点前就能完工
I know. I'd be done by nine.
九点前 没问题吧？
By nine, right?
没问题
Yeah.
我会带蛋糕回来
I'll bring back a cake.
我保证
I promise.
……雅加达的暴动仍在持续
...continued disturbances in Jakarta,
但建议美国公民……
but are advising U.S. citizens...
雅加达 那是在哪儿 中东吗？
Jakarta. Where is that, Middle East?
没印象 肯定是个国家
Doesn't ring a bell. It's definitely a country.
要么就是亚洲哪个地方？
Or maybe part of Asia?
雅加达不是国家
Jakarta isn't a country.
而亚洲的某个地方也可以是个国家
Being a part of Asia isn't mutually exclusive with being a country,
事实上 它是印度尼西亚的首都
and in fact, it's the capital of Indonesia.
妈的 咱还有希望啊
Shit. Hope for us yet.
好了
All right.
赶紧解决 我们送你上学
Finish up quick, we'll drop you off.
我还在吃我的蛋壳呢
I'm still eating my eggshells.
你还有七分钟
You got seven minutes.
你的T恤穿反了
Your t-shirt's inside out.
妈的
Shit.
他脑子短路了
He's losin' it.
莎拉！
Sarah!
这不是邻居么！
Hey, neighbor!
噢 你好
Oh, Hi.
康妮刚问起你呢 你有一阵子没过来了
Connie was askin' after you, since you haven't been over in a while.
逗他们开心
Make 'em happy.
我可以放学后过来 但 也就能 待一会儿？
I could come by after school, but just for, like, a little bit?
能待一会儿是一会儿
She'll take whatcha got.
你们可以一起烘焙 或者啥的
Y'all can bake, whatever.
说到烘焙
Speakin' of,
我们这儿还剩了不少
we got a lotta extra here.
你们要吃饼干吗？
Y'all want some biscuits?
爸 你不是爱吃饼干么
Dad, you love biscuits.
我确实喜欢
I do.
但我正限碳水呢
But I'm on Atkins.
限什么？
On what now?
就是……我说
It's, you know what?
我们得走了 不过莎拉晚点会过去
We gotta run, but Sarah'll be by later.
你想让她待多久 她就待多久
She'll stay as long as you want.
跟你们好好讲讲限碳水
Tell ya all about Atkins.
好啊！我这就告诉康妮
Great! I'll let Connie know.
真行
Solid.
听你们聊天可真他妈带劲
Can't tell you how exciting it was listenin' to that fuckin' conversation.
把烟掐了
Put that out.
祝你生日快乐啊
Happy birthday to you.
沙漠风暴行动
退伍军人
德州 奥斯汀市
9月26日
照我的要求把图一模一样地画下来
Want you to write this diagram out exactly as I have it.
始终是主语和谓语
Always subject and predicate.
活出声色
人生无限！
学不在学校
而在人生
记得微笑
动词和名词
Verb and noun.
好了 句子是 “你要去哪儿？” 主语是你
Okay, the sentence is, "Where are you going?" Subject is you.
是你要去
You are going.
谓语
Predicate.
哪儿 是副词
Where, adverb.
你们明白了吗？好了 点头或摇头 让我看到
You see it? Okay. Have some nods, shaking of heads.
我保证你们将来会用到这些的
I swear you will use this later in life.
所以你们会坐在这里 相信我
Believe me, that's why you're here.
好吗？所以……
Okay? So...
是的 你们得弄明白这些！
Yes, you need to know this!
是的 你们下周测试会考到！
Yes, it's on your test next week!
作业要在明天下课前上交！
Homework is due end of class tomorrow!
孤星钟表珠宝店
买·卖·修
黎
巴
嫩
五折
二十
Twenty.
这么便宜？
That's it?
行 那三十
Okay, 30.
二十就好
Twenty's good.
发条的事 我现在就修
It's a spring. I'll do it right now.
吵一整天了 真的
All day. I swear.
我们要关门了
We're closing.
今天不营业了
We're done for today.
才3点15 我们7点才关门
It's 3:15, we close at 7.
我很抱歉 他没法完工了
I'm very sorry. He cannot finish.
我已经完工了
I'm already finished.
你应该回家
You should go home.
孤星钟表珠宝店
买·卖·修
- 你可来了 亲爱的 - 抱歉
-There you are, sweetie. -Sorry.
我都要担心了
I was gettin' worried.
我刚去给我爸取了点东西
I was getting something for my dad.
嗨 默西
Hi, Mercy.
嘿 一切还好吗？我是指 新闻上说啥了吗？
Hey, is everything okay? Like, on the news?
新闻咋了 亲爱的？
Like what, hon?
也没有 只是今天路上有很多警察之类的
Well, no, there was just a lot of police and stuff on the road today.
每天都是如此 不是吗？
Well, that's true every day, innit?
外边那些人得让耶稣给他们正正心思
People out there need to get right with Jesus.
三颗钉子 一个十字架 正如四字神名
Three nails, plus one cross, equals four-given.
我觉着咱可以做点曲奇饼
I was thinkin' we'd make some cookies.
巧克力碎的？
Chocolate chip?
提子干的
Raisin.
尝尝嘛 妈妈 提子是绿色的
C'mon, Mama. It's green.
你可喜欢了
You love that.
可算好了！
Here we go!
我不知道我为什么要和她说话
I don't know why I talk to her.
她已经聋透了
She's completely deaf.
能过来帮把手吗？
You wanna give me a hand?
马上来！
Be right there!
嘿 阿德勒太太？
Hey, Mrs. Adler?
我可以借这个吗？
Could I borrow this?
当然了
Yeah, sure.
这是丹尼的
It's one of Danny's.
你知道吗？我爸很快就会回来了
You know what? My dad's gonna be back real soon.
- 我得走了 - 你确定吗？
-I should go. -You sure?
- 嗯 - 那你得带上些曲奇
-Yeah. -Well, you're takin' some cookies.
市内暴力事件频发
No comment today from the Austin Police Department
有人认为也许罪魁祸首是一种新的街头毒品
regarding a rash of violent incidents across the city,
对此 奥斯汀警署今日未予置评
some suggesting a new street drug may be to blame.
我们稍后继续 曼努埃拉·桑切斯在现场报导……
More on that when we return, with Manuela Sanchez reporting live...
你可算锁了一次门
You locked the door for once.
干得好
Good job.
是啊
Yeah.
- 10点了 - 我知道
-It's 10. -I know.
他们给错了露头砖的尺寸
They gave us the wrong size for the headers.
这些对你来说毫无意义 不好意思
That doesn't mean anything to ya. I'm sorry.
蛋糕呢？
Where's the cake?
该死
Shit.
行不行啊 老兄
C'mon, man.
我明天给咱们买一个
I'll get us one tomorrow.
发誓 要么就不给你礼物了
Swear, or you don't get your present.
你给我准备了礼物？
You got me a present?
快发誓
Swear.
我以性命发誓
On my life.
哇哦
Wow.
给你修好了
Fixed it for you.
- 有修好吗？ - 什么？
-Did you? -What?
我什么都听不到
I don't hear anything.
这招好差劲
That was lame.
- 你好差劲 - 是啊 我知道
-You're lame. -Yeah, I know.
你哪来的修表钱？
Where'd you get the money for this?
贩毒 我贩超猛的毒
Drugs. I sell hardcore drugs.
比我干的活儿要强
It's better than what I do.
只花了20刀 我从你那儿偷的
It was only $20, which I stole from you.
本可以偷60刀的 但我把剩下的钱放回去了
I could've stolen 60, but I put the change back
因为我是个诚实的小偷
because I'm an honest thief.
再说了 心意更重要
Besides, it's the thought that counts.
而你自己永远都不会去修 所以
And you were never gonna do it for yourself, so.
谢谢你
Thank you.
还有一个礼物
There's one more.
从阿德勒家借来的
Borrowed it from the Adlers.
柯蒂斯和毒蛇2
这次是家事
喔 这版还附带了删减片段
Oh, this is the one with the deleted scenes.
“我见过
最好的
表演之一”
“全世界
都在等
的续集”
对啊 想想那些得有多烂
Yeah, imagine how bad those have to be.
快 放进去 趁着你的生日还没过
C'mon, pop it in. While it's still your birthday.
可别睡着了
Don't fall asleep.
我当然不会
'Course, I won't.
这片子太吸引人了
It's too riveting.
喂？
Hello?
乔尔 是我
Joel, it's me.
我没事
I'm okay.
那？
Yeah?
但我进号子了
But I'm in jail.
妈了个逼的
Goddammit.
这次不是我的错
Wasn't my fault this time.
我当时在酒吧里 有个人突然发了疯 朝着女服务员挥拳头
I was at the bar, some guy goes crazy, starts swingin' at a waitress,
我就上去了 把那人打晕 条子就来了——
I stepped in, knocked him out, cops show up--
听着 这些都他妈无所谓
Look, it doesn't fuckin' matter.
你得把我保出来
You gotta bail me out.
现在？
Now?
今天是周五 你今晚不把我弄出来 我就得待上一整个周末
It's Friday, you don't get me out tonight, I'm in here all weekend.
这地方他妈疯了 乔尔
It's a fuckin' madhouse, Joel.
- 我得出去 - 哪个监狱？特拉维斯县的？
-I gotta get out. -Well, which jail? Travis County?
对 10号路上的
Yeah, on 10th.
操 汤米
Goddammit, Tommy.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
求你了
Please.
好吧
Okay.
他娘的蠢货
Fuckin' idiot.
爸？
Dad?
爸？！
Dad?!
……室内 执法与急救服务
...indoors. Law enforcement and emergency services
全国警报
主要入境点系统
发布
紧急行动
通知
就在当地并将联系提供进一步指示
are in the area and will be in contact with further instructions.
待在室内 执法与急救服务……
Stay indoors, law enforcement...
乖 乖 默西
Easy. Easy, Mercy.
你在外面干什么呢 小子？
What're you doing out here, boy?
来 我们回家
C'mon, let's get you home.
快来 默西 别闹了
C'mon, Mercy. Please.
默西
Mercy!
阿德勒太太？
Mrs. Adler?
帮帮我
Help me.
进车里！快点！
Get in the truck! Right now!
上车！
Move!
乔尔 我们怎么办 ？
What are we doin', Joel?
你杀了她
You killed her.
宝贝 我很抱歉
Baby, I'm sorry.
乔尔 我们得走了
Joel, we gotta go.
莎拉 听我说
Sarah, listen to me.
病的不止是阿德勒一家
It's not just the Adlers.
但我们要勇敢 我们要逃出去
But we're gonna be brave, and we're gonna get outta this.
嘿 快走 来吧
Hey. Let's go. Come on.
上车
Get in.
乔尔？
Joel?
丹妮丝 你快回屋子里！
Denise, you get back inside the house!
你把门锁紧了！马上！！
You lock your doors! Now!
快点 快点 进来！
C'mon, c'mon, get in!
- 系好安全带 - 抓稳了
-Get your seat belt on. -Hold on.
上帝啊 乔尔！
Jesus Christ, Joel!
- 你上7——  - 71号公路 我知道
-You take 70-- -71, I know.
←奥斯汀
圣马科斯→
医院→
西
东
- 爸爸——  - 我们也不清楚
-Daddy-- -We don't know.
他们说是病毒 某种寄生虫
They're saying it's a virus. Some kind of parasite.
是恐怖分子弄出来的吗？
Is it from terrorists?
我们不清楚
We don't know.
我们也病了吗？
Are we sick?
没 当然没有
No. Of course not.
为什么有爆炸？
Why did things blow up?
手机没信号 也收不到广播
No cellphone, no radio.
刚才新闻还讲个不停
Minute ago, newsman wouldn't shut up.
你怎么知道？
How do you know?
什么？
What?
你怎么知道我们没病？
How do you know we're not sick?
他们说病的主要是城里的人
They're saying it's mostly people in the city.
所以他们把高速路封锁了
That's why they got the highway blocked off.
天啊
God.
是吉米家
It's Jimmy's place.
阿德勒家有时候会把奶奶带进城里
The Adlers would take Nana into the city.
去医院拿药之类的
To the hospital for stuff.
没错 他们确实 也许就是因为这个
That's right. They would. That's probably why.
但是 你得去很多次才会得病 对吧？
But, you'd have to go a lot, right?
我们没事 相信我
We're fine. Trust me.
好吧
All right.
这里！在这里！
Here! Right here!
- 嘿！ - 你在干嘛？
-Hey! -What are you doin'?
- 有小孩 乔尔 - 我们也有 向前开
-Got a kid, Joel. -So do we. Keep driving.
我们可以让他们坐后边
We could put them in the back.
还会有别人来的
Somebody else'll come along.
操！所有人都他妈想一块儿去了
Fuck! Everybody had the same fuckin' idea.
我开不过去
I can't get through this.
好了 我们先想想 我们先想想
All right. Let's think it through, we'll think it through.
- 操！ - 这样 我们走草地
-Fuck! -All right, take the field.
穿过去 然后从西边再上路
We cut across and we pick up on the west side.
行行行 西边 西边 好
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. West, west, all right.
好了 坐稳
All right, hang on.
操！操他妈的军队
Shit! Fuckin' army.
这不是好事吗？
Isn't that good?
对他们来说好
It's good for them,
但那儿是我们要上的高速
but that's the highway we're tryin' to get to.
好了 车别停 向北走
All right, keep movin'. Head north.
可能会有很多人
Could be a lotta people.
得 我们不能往南走
Well, we can't go south,
不能去东边 不能去西边
we can't go east, we can't go west.
我们他妈还能去哪儿？
Hell else we supposed to go?
汤米 走了！
Tommy, come on!
好
Yeah.
好 前边这地方我知道
Yeah, I know that place.
- 这么走可以 - 现在可以 之后呢？
-This can work. -Yeah, but then what?
我不知道 墨西哥吧 反正越远越好
I don't know. Mexico. Just far, far as we can.
还剩多少油？
How much gas?
四分之三缸
Three-quarter tank.
穿过镇子 河边有个高尔夫球场 直接穿过去
Go through town, golf course by the river, straight across,
我们从封锁区另一头上高速
we pick up the highway on the other side of the blockade,
然后就出去了
then we're out.
也许到处都有
Maybe it's everywhere.
也许根本无处可去
Maybe there's nowhere to go.
我了个操？！
What the fuck?!
狗娘养的 得绕过去
Son of a bitch. Gotta go around.
抓稳了！
Grab somethin'!
好了 继续开 继续开
All right, keep goin', keep goin'.
我操 汤米！
Shit. Tommy!
汤米 你不能停这儿
Tommy, you can't stop here.
- 我不能朝人开 - 你开玩笑吗？
-I can't drive through 'em all. -Are you serious?
只管往前开！
Just keep goin'!
走 走 走 倒 倒 倒
Go, go, go. Back, back, back,
-倒 倒 倒 倒！ - 别催了！
-back, back, back, back! -I'm trying!
汤米 开快点！我们得走！
Tommy, go faster! We gotta go!
我在开了！哪儿他妈都走不了！
I'm tryin'! There's nowhere to fuckin' go!
找个巷子！
Find an alley!
哪有巷子？哪里都是人！
What alley? There's people everywhere!
直接他妈的碾过去！我们得马上离开这条街！
Roll the fuck over them! We gotta get off this street now!
我一直在这么做 乔尔
That's what I'm tryin' to do, Joel.
我们会没事的 继续开就行
We're gonna be okay. Just keep drivin'.
爸？
Dad?
我操！
Holy shit!
走 走！
Move. Move!
莎拉 莎拉
Sarah, Sarah.
待在这儿 别动
Stay right there. Don't move.
汤米 你没事吧？
Tommy, you okay?
嗯 我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
莎拉 不要看
Sarah, don't look.
你看我就好 好吗？
You look at me, okay?
我很抱歉 宝贝 我明白 我明白
I'm sorry, baby, I know, I know.
过来 用手抱住我
Come here. Put your arms around me.
过来 过来
Come here, come here.
有我在 有我在
I got you. I got you.
我在
Got you.
你还好吗？你还好吗？
Are you okay? Are you okay?
- 我的脚踝 - 好 我知道了
-My ankle. -All right, okay.
我们得离开这条街！妈的！
We gotta get off the street! Shit!
汤米？！
Tommy?!
汤米？
Tommy?
汤米！
Tommy!
朝着河走！我会找到路的
Head to the river! I'll find a way.
带她出去 乔尔！快走！
Get her outta here, Joel! Go!
我们不能抛下他
We can't leave him.
他会没事的
He'll be fine.
跑得动吗？
Can you run?
不行
No.
眼睛盯住我
You keep your eyes on me.
好
Okay.
好吗？
Okay?
好
Okay.
别看其它地方
And don't look anywhere else.
好
Alright.
没事的 宝贝 你很安全
It's okay, baby. You're safe.
别动！
Don't move!
我女儿受伤了 脚踝伤了
My daughter's hurt. Her ankle.
停在原地！
Stop right there!
好
Okay.
别紧张 我们没生病！
Easy now. We're not sick!
我这儿有两个平民在河边 其中一个受伤了
I got two civilians by the river, one of 'em injured.
脚踝受伤
Ankle.
汤米叔叔怎么办？
What about Uncle Tommy?
我们先把你送到安全的地方
We're gonna get you somewhere safe first.
然后我们再回去找他 好吗？
Then we'll go back for him, okay?
- 好 - 好
-Okay. -Okay.
对不起 重复一遍？
I'm sorry, repeat?
嘿！没说你可以动
Hey! No one told you to move.
是 长官
Yes, sir.
我们没生病
We're not sick.
长官
Sir,
我们没生病！
we are not sick!
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
请不要
Please, don't.
我的天啊
Oh God.
不 噢 不
No. Oh no.
不 不 不
No, no. No.
没事 你没事
Okay, You're okay.
没事的 把手移开 宝贝
You're okay. Move your hand, baby.
把手移开
Move your hand.
我知道 宝贝 我知道 我知道 我知道 我知道
I know, baby, I know, I know, I know, I know.
我知道很疼
I know it hurts.
好了 别往下看 往上看 往上看
Alright. Don't look down, look up, look up.
没事的 宝贝 你没事 你没事
Come on, baby. You're okay, you're okay.
我知道 我知道 我知道 我知道 宝贝 我知道 我知道
I know, I know, I know, I know, baby, I know, I know.
我知道这样很疼
I know this hurts.
你会没事的
You're gonna be okay.
好了 宝贝 宝贝 宝贝 听我说
All right, baby, baby, baby, listen to me.
我要把你抱起来 好吗？我要抱你起来
I gotta get you up, okay? I gotta get you up.
好吗？来吧
All right? You come on.
来吧 我知道 宝贝
You come on. I know, baby.
不 不 我知道 我知道 我知道 我知道 我知道 我知道
No, no. I know, I know, I know, I know, I know, I know.
汤米 帮我！
Tommy, help me!
乔尔
Joel.
别这样 宝贝女儿
C'mon, baby girl.
别这样 宝贝女儿 我得让你起来
C'mon, baby girl, I gotta get you up.
别这样
Come on.
来 我们起来
Come on, we'll get up.
来吧 宝贝女儿
Come on, baby girl.
别这样 别——求你了
Come on, come-- Please.
二十年后
波士顿
2023年
国会街
欢迎
FEDRA隔离区
未经允许，不得进入
检查站
走此路
↑
欢迎
举报真菌感染迹象
完全感染所需时间
立刻向当局举报真菌感染
咳嗽不停
口齿不清
肌肉痉挛
情绪波动
安全从你开始
颈部、面部、头部
5-15分钟
躯干、臂、
肩、手
2-8小时
腿、足
12-24小时
这样你就不会跌下椅子了
We don't want you falling out of the chair.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
你是一个人吗？
Are you alone?
还有
And,
这里是怎么弄的？
how did you get this?
这儿会有一点点痒
There's gonna be a little tickle right here.
听我说 给你吃完药之后
What if I told you that after we gave you some medicine,
我们就给你吃你最喜欢的食物
we're gonna find you your favorite food to eat.
你觉得怎么样？
Would you like that?
然后我们给你找些新衣服……和玩具
And then we'll get you some new clothes... and toys.
想玩多少有多少
As many as you wanna play with.
只是一根小针头
It's just a little needle.
没事的
It's okay.
你很安全
You're safe.
我做不到
I can't.
十张
Ten.
还有别的活儿吗？
You got anything else?
今天没了
Nothin' today.
明天我们有扫大街
Tomorrow, we got street sweeping,
还有下水道维修
or sewer maintenance.
哪个报酬更多？
Which pays more?
弄屎的那个
That'd be the one with the shit.
晚一班 下午四点开始
Late crew. 4 P.M. start.
宵禁时间
晚六点到早六点
任何人未经FEDRA允许上街
都将被立即逮捕
举报真菌感染迹象
咳嗽不停
口齿不清
肌肉痉挛
情绪波动
安全从你开始
普通鞋带 1张配给卡
靴子鞋带 2张配给卡
杰森·崔
Jason Choi,
违反条例EMC342.3
violation of EMC 342.3,
未经许可离开隔离区
unauthorized exit from a Quarantine Zone.
玛丽亚·埃利西亚诺
Maria Elisiano,
违反条例EMC342.7
violation of EMC 342.7,
未经许可进入隔离区
unauthorized entry into a Quarantine Zone.
你们都在军事法庭上接受了审判
Each of you have been tried in a military court of justice,
并都被军事法庭陪审团认定有罪
and each of you having been found guilty by the court martial panel,
将被处以死刑
and with a sentence of death by execution,
根据EMPA第1条第5款的授权……
as empowered under the EMPA, Article 1, Section 5...
快点
C'mon.
不然我就当场毙了你
Or I could just shoot you.
那你之后该怎么办呢？
Yeah, but then what would you do?
你少了五张
You're short five.
不得入内
授权人员除外
危险
洒水器
4号控制室
氧合的？
Oxy?
氢合的
Hydro.
放多久了？
How old?
三个月
Three months.
亚特兰大的？
From Atlanta?
我不知道他哪儿弄来的
I don't know where he gets 'em from.
我只知道是真货
I just know they're real.
如果是真货 那就是亚特兰大的
If it's real, it's from Atlanta.
FEDRA在那边的隔离区有个工厂
FEDRA's got a factory down there in the QZ.
FEDRA：Federal Disaster Response Agency（联邦救灾署）的缩写，
是控制隔离区和美国军队的机构，也是前美国政府的残余组成部分
据说只产两样东西
Supposedly only makes two things.
药片与子弹 子弹与药片
Pills and bullets, bullets and pills.
我猜 你杀的人越多 入睡就越难
Well, the more you shoot people, the harder it is to sleep, I guess.
你还用猜？
You guess?
到底要不要？
You want 'em or not?
袋子得还我
I need the bag back.
车子准备得怎么样了？
How we doin' with the vehicle?
都弄好了
All set.
修车厂就差最后一个人要收买
Just had to get one last guy in the depot to buy in.
好 要多少钱？
Okay, how much?
他们四个加上我……
Four of them on that shift plus me...
一共六百张
six hundred total.
听着 那些卡车当破烂堆着是有原因的
Look, those trucks are shitheaped for a reason.
而且车上没电池 我知道
And they don't have any batteries. I know.
我给其他人两百张……
I can see about 200 for the other guys...
给你两百张
two hundred for you.
成交
Deal.
嘿 听我句劝
Hey, do yourself a favor,
这几天晚上就别上街了
stay off the streets for the next few nights.
操蛋火萤一整周都在到处搞爆炸
Fuckin' Fireflies been blowin' shit up all week.
今早我们有两人中了枪
Two of our guys got shot this morning.
老大让我们连值两轮班
Boss has got us working doubles.
大家都又累又敏感
Guys are jumpy and tired.
黑灯瞎火的 很容易误会
It's easy to make a mistake in the dark.
注意安全
Stay safe.
嗯 你也是
Yeah, you too.
当你迷失在黑暗中时
就寻找光明
你想要我说什么 泰丝？
What do you want me to say, Tess?
我什么都没要你说
I'm not askin' you to say anything.
确实
Sure.
我本来没打算要敲你竹杠
It's not like I planned on rippin' you off.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
那好
Well,
我们就让事情过去怎样？
how about we just let it go?
你还能怎么做？
What else are you gonna do?
你要把我留在这儿？
Ya gonna keep me here?
杀了我？
Kill me?
泰丝 别这样
Tess, c'mon.
那 罗伯特 你要怎样？
Then, Robert, what do ya want?
我希望你把这事彻底忘了
I want you to forget this ever happened.
已经忘了
Done.
别这样
Don't do that.
怎样？
What?
只是块卡车电池而已 我付了钱给你
It's just a truck battery. I paid you for it,
你卖给了别人 还花了我的钱
you sold it to someone else, and you spent my money.
我是说 你以为这种破事我没干过？
I mean, you think I've never done shit like that?
我手下揍了你
My guys fucked you up.
行 那就教他们规矩
Yeah, so discipline them.
砍他们根手指 或者随你他妈做啥
You cut off a finger or whatever the fuck you want.
我无所谓 反正是你的人
I don't care. They're your fuckin' guys.
那你的人呢？因为他要看见你这样
What about your guy? 'Cause when he sees you,
我是说 站在我的立场考虑下
I mean, put yourself in my shoes.
听着 他听我的话
Look, he answers to me.
所以我向你保证他不会碰你
So, I give you my word that he won't hurt you.
我会告诉他我被随便什么人偷袭了
I'll tell him that I got jumped by some guys,
然后咱们这事儿就他妈这么过去了
and then you and I can just move the fuck on.
得了 你的破事基本上把我这一周都毁了
Now your shit has pretty much ruined my week,
我就想回家喝酒 喝到我的脸不疼为止
and I'd like to go home and drink 'til my face stops hurting.
所以 我们完事没？
So, are we good?
行
Yeah.
所有公民必须
All citizens must clear
马上离开外围区域
the surrounding area immediately.
在FEDRA当局允许前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
所有公民必须马上离开外围区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在FEDRA当局允许前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
所有公民必须马上离开外围区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在FEDRA当局允许前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
所有公民必须马上离开外围区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在FEDRA当局允许前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
所有公民必须马上离开外围区域
All citizens must clear the surrounding area immediately.
在FEDRA当局允许前不得返回
Do not return until FEDRA authorities permit.
妈的
Oh shit.
是火萤 在上边！
Firefly, up top!
立刻解放波士顿 狗娘养的！
Free Boston now, motherfuckers!
他们在开枪 他们在朝我们开枪
They're shooting. They're shooting at us.
跪在地上
On your knees.
跪在地上！
On your knees!
不 不！我不是火——
No, no! I'm not a F--
我不是火萤！
I'm not a Firefly!
缓慢且清楚地从1数到10
Count slowly and clearly from one to 10.
一 二 三 四——
One, two, three, four--
缓慢
Slowly,
且清楚
and clearly.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
四
Four.
五
Five.
六
Six.
七
Seven.
八
Eight.
操……
Fuck...
你
you.
然后伸出你的——
And hold out your--
- 说出你的名字 缓慢且清楚地说 - 维罗妮卡
-State your name, slowly and clearly. -Veronica.
和昨天一样 和前天也一样
Same as yesterday, and the day before,
和大前天也一样 还有大大——
and the day before, and the--
嘿 会有人来找我的
Hey, people are gonna come looking for me.
FEDRA的人 你听到了吗？
People from FEDRA. You hear me?
放我出去 不然你们会付出代价 狗娘养的！
Let me out or you're gonna pay, motherfuckers!
我根本不该在这里！
I'm not supposed to be here!
当你迷失在黑暗中时
嘿 要排队的！
Hey, there's a line!
“告诉爸爸，是个女孩
"Tell Dad it's a girl.
“那样很好，对吗？
"That would be good, right?
“他一直想要个孙女
"He wanted a granddaughter.
爱你的，贝卡。”
Love, Becca."
结束留言 复读
End message. Read back.
留言正确 73-K奥兰多 完毕
Correct, 73-K Orlando. Out.
什么都没有？
Nothin'?
有没有可能消息晚上来的？
Is there any chance it's comin' in at night?
你睡着了 就错过了？
You're sleepin', you miss it?
我睡觉的时候 加布里埃拉在听 或者是我的儿子
When I'm sleeping, Gabriela listens, or my son.
聪明的那个 不是另一个 上帝保佑
The smart one, not the other one, God bless him.
如果汤米回消息了 我们会知道的
If Tommy responded, we'd know.
- 你和塔那边也有联系？ - 每天都有
-And you're talkin' to the tower? -Every day.
他们转达了你的消息 他们之后就没看见过他
They gave him your message, they haven't seen or heard
或者听到消息 就这样
from him since, and that's it.
也没过多久
It hasn't been that long.
已经三周了
It's been three weeks.
他从未失联超过一天
It's never taken him more than a day to respond.
我确信他没事
I'm sure he's okay.
让我看看塔在哪儿
Show me where the tower is.
你不是认真的吧
You can't be serious.
乔尔 塔在怀俄明州
Joel, it's in Wyoming.
这么多开放区？
All this open country?
我是说 你很有本事
I mean, you're a capable guy,
但外边有比感染者更可怕的东西
but there are worse things than Infected out there.
我在这上头啥都能听着
I hear everything on this.
外边有强盗 有蓄奴的——
There are raiders, there are slavers--
但你“确信”汤米没事？
But you're "sure" Tommy's okay?
这是科迪塔
It's the Cody tower...
在第四隔离区 但我不清楚具体——
Q-Bar 4, but I don't know exactly wh--
下一位！
Next!
你知道吗 乔尔……
You know what, Joel...
乔尔！
Joel!
我被几个人偷袭了
I got jumped by a couple guys.
什么人？
What guys?
就是几个小屁孩
Just a couple teenagers.
随口说了几句 也许不该的
Said some shit, probably shouldn't've.
算了吧 你知道这些人是疫情爆发后出生的
Come on. You know these guys were born after the outbreak.
没学过吵架 就开始抡拳头了
Never learned how to argue. They just start swingin'.
一帮19岁的混账东西
Fuckin' 19-year-old pieces of shit.
你还活着是个奇迹
It's a miracle you're alive.
我们任何一个人活着都是奇迹
It's a miracle any of us are alive.
这些伤口不是新的
These aren't new.
不是
No.
我在FEDRA的拘留所待了一整天
I was in FEDRA lockup all day.
不过 这些也无所谓了
Anyway, it doesn't matter.
我需要你冷静下来
I need you to take a breath.
怎么了？
What?
乔尔——
Joel--
怎么了？
What?
偷袭我的是罗伯特的人
The guys who jumped me were with Robert.
他把我们的电池卖给了别人
He sold our battery to someone else.
没什么大不了的 这种逼事常有
Nothing's lost. Shit like this is gonna happen.
现在我们振作起来
Now we just shake it off,
然后拿回我们的卡 或者电池
and we go get our cards back, or the battery.
我需要那个电池 泰丝
I need the battery, Tess.
缺了那玩意儿 车子根本没法用
Truck's no good without one,
如果我不尽快找到汤米 他可能就死在外面了
and if I don't get to Tommy soon, he's gonna die out there.
行吧 操他的
Okay, fuck it.
我们会把钱和电池都拿回来
We get our money back and the battery.
但是 乔尔 听好了
But, Joel, listen,
罗伯特对你怕得不行
Robert is terrified of you.
所以 你要是跟克林特·伊斯特伍德似地走出去
So, you march outta here all Clint Eastwood,
他肯定会听到风声 悄悄开溜
he's gonna get wind of it and skip.
我需要你放松下来
I need you to take a breath.
他把电池卖给谁了？
Who'd he sell it to?
不知道
Don't know.
好 那他在哪儿？
Well, where is he?
不知道
Don't know.
暂时
Yet.
我们会把他揪出来 别冒冒失失的
But we're gonna find out, quietly.
明白吗？
Understand?
虽然我向罗伯特保证过你不会动他
Now I promised Robert that you wouldn't hurt him.
但我希望你把他好好收拾一顿
But I would very much like for you to hurt him.
走 把那个王八蛋揪出来
So let's go hunt that motherfucker down,
拿回我们的电池 我们的车
and get our battery and our truck,
然后我们就动身去找汤米
and then we'll go find Tommy.
行吗？
All right?
行
All right.
东南3号区的人到位了没？
The team in place at Southeast 3?
我让他们先待命
I held them back.
我有话要问
I have some questions.
问吧
Okay.
我们一直在炸毁无意义的FEDRA目标
We've been blowing up meaningless FEDRA targets
这些目标遍布整个隔离区 炸了整整两周
spread out all over the QZ, for two weeks.
已经损失了四个人 可我们还要——
We've already lost four people, and we're--
这么做有什么意义？
What's the point of this?
这就是你想问的？
Is that your question?
其中之一
That's one of them.
我的回答是 他妈的服从命令
My answer is to follow fuckin' orders.
还有 你为什么把个不知来路的丫头锁在房间里？
And why do you have some random girl locked in a room?
而你安排看守她的人连个屁都不跟我放？
And the guys you have guarding her won't tell me shit?
我们的人一直在问我究竟是什么情况 我什么都说不出
Our people are asking what's going on, and I don't know what to tell them.
让他们执行他妈的命令
Tell them to follow fuckin' orders.
你们俩 去东南3号区 马上
You two, go to Southeast 3. Now.
- 金 - 玛琳
-Kim. -Marlene.
我们正处在反抗军事独裁的斗争中
We are in a war against a military dictatorship
为的是重建民主和自由
to restore democracy and freedom.
这话对不对？
Does that sound about right?
然后？
Yes?
我们赢了吗？
Are we winning?
我们打败本地的FEDRA了吗？
Are we beating FEDRA here?
有哪儿的火萤击败了FEDRA吗？
Are the Fireflies beating FEDRA anywhere?
反抗不是一朝一夕
Rebellion takes time.
你已经战斗20年了
You fight for 20 years
哪里都没有打下来 这不是反抗
and you get nowhere, you're not a rebellion.
只不过是涂鸦
Just spray paint.
我们并没有与FEDRA在隔离区“全境”作战
We're not hitting FEDRA "all over" the QZ.
而是在这 这 这 这 以及这里袭击他们
We hit 'em here, here, here, here, here.
我们现在在哪儿？
Where are we right now?
在其他地方袭击FEDRA都可以 就是这里不行
I want FEDRA everywhere but here.
我要FEDRA的注意力尽可能从这里移开 因为今晚
I want them as distracted as possible because tonight,
波士顿的每一位火萤成员都要集合到这座建筑里
every Firefly in Boston is gonna gather in this building,
我们要离开这个隔离区 不再回来
and we are gonna leave the QZ. Permanently.
我们要撤退了？
We're quitting?
不
No.
我们要带着锁在房间里的那个小丫头往西走
We're taking that random girl locked in that room west.
这是我们的人从塞勒姆的无线电塔发来的
From our guy in the radio tower in Salem.
这是真的吗？
Is this real?
我相信是真的
I believe it is.
别告诉其他人
Keep it quiet.
无论你需要什么
Whatever you need.
不惜一切代价
Whatever it takes.
我们会把她送到该去的地方
We'll get her where she needs to go.
嘿 朋友
Hey, friend.
别担心 我什么都不要
Don't worry. I don't want anything.
当你迷失在——
But if you're feelin' lost--
敢跟我说“就寻找光明” 我就打断你下巴
You tell me to "look for the light" and I'll break your jaw.
呃 花了几张卡 但拿到那家伙的线索了
Well, it cost us a couple of cards, but we got him.
据说他要把电池带到一座有红色标记的楼里
He's supposedly takin' the battery to a red-tagged building.
记住地址 在斯第曼街和十字街交口
But get this, corner of Stillman and Cross.
米格尔待过的那栋楼
The one Miguel used to use.
对 我也觉得是
Yeah, I'm thinkin' so.
我们可以走干草市场地下的那条地铁隧道
We can take the subway tunnel under Haymarket,
从地下进大楼 给罗伯特一个惊喜
get into the building from below, and take Robert by surprise.
好好回报这个混蛋
Pay this fucker back.
噢 天呐
Oh, my God.
啊！你个混蛋！
Agh! You fucker!
一 二 三 四——
One, two, three, four--
你不怕我
You're not scared.
那就解开铁链
Then unlock me.
不如先说一句“谢谢你”？
How about we start with "thank you"?
凭什么？
For what?
凭我救了你一命？
For saving your life?
我让他们别朝你开枪
I am the one who told 'em not to shoot you,
如果你还记得
if you recall.
确实
Yeah.
你为什么要阻止他们？
Why did you stop them?
晚点说这个
We'll get to that.
那么 维罗妮卡
So, Veronica,
你感觉怎么样？
how ya feelin'?
没变化
The same.
我会死吗？
Is it gonna happen?
不会
No.
那我能走吗？
So, can I go?
不能
No.
我不会和任何人说起这个事情
I won't tell anyone about any of this.
我发誓
I swear.
那你打算去哪儿？
Where you gonna go?
回到FEDRA的军校？
Back to FEDRA military school?
你就那么想当个士兵？
You that anxious to be a soldier?
你觉得那是我选的？
You think I chose that place?
我还是个婴儿的时候 就被他们送到那了
They put me there when I was a baby.
那地方是给孤儿的
It's for orphans.
不是“他们”把你送到那
"They" didn't put you there.
是我做的
I did.
艾莉
Ellie.
你他妈是我亲妈还是什么？
You my fucking mom or something?
我看起来像是你妈？
Do I look like your mom?
是不像
Nooo, you do not.
我叫玛琳
My name is Marlene.
波士顿隔离区的火萤组织领导人
I'm the leader of the Fireflies in the Boston QZ.
为什么一个恐怖分子要把我丢给FEDRA？
Why would a terrorist dump me with FEDRA?
因为那儿对你最安全 事实也的确如此
Because it's where you'd be safest, and you were safe there
结果你偷偷溜了出来
until you decided to sneak out.
还有 “恐怖分子”？
And "terrorist"?
你认为莱莉也是恐怖分子吗？
Was Riley a terrorist?
你为什么不让我回家？
Why won't you let me go home?
因为你身上有一项我们任何人都想象不到的重大使命
Because you have a greater purpose than any of us could've ever imagined.
所以 我们会在今晚出发 带上你一起走
So we're leaving tonight, and we're taking you with us.
他到了
He's here.
等我五分钟
Five minutes.
我将要告诉你的话 绝对不能让其他人知道
What I'm about to tell you cannot be repeated to anyone.
如果你跟别人说了 我向你保证
Because if you do, I assure you
你会没命
you will die.
干草市场 入口 B38
西南维护站
未经授权不得进入
仅限马萨诸塞湾交通局员工进入
好了
Okay.
准备好了吗？
Ready?
好了
Yeah.
就是这个
That's the one.
我操
Oh fuck.
操他妈的
Oh shit.
这货死透了
This one's done.
对
Yeah.
我知道 我只是——
I know. I just--
没料到会有这个
I wasn't expecting it.
看来上次它不在？
Take it he wasn't down here last time?
不在
No.
你觉得它是在被感染后才来到地下？
You think he came down after he was infected?
或许它是来地下以后才被感染的
Well, maybe down here is where he was infected.
得了 走吧
Let's keep movin'.
看上去他们调了整个结构
It's like they reframed the whole structure.
可能是在80年代改的
Probably in the '80s.
人们缩减出租型公寓的面积
Everyone was cutting down on apartment sizes
为的是能卖出更多出售型公寓
to sell more condos.
“感谢乔尔·米勒带来的'建筑小知识'”
"This has been 'Construction Corner' with Joel Miller."
我们还要爬多远？
How far up we goin'?
到了
This far.
瞧 这个入口通向走廊
So, this opens into the hallway.
这他妈搞什么鬼？有人用钢琴挡住门吗？
What the fuck? Someone put a piano in front of this?
你闻到了吗？
You smell that?
对 是火药
Yeah, gunpowder.
泰丝
Tess.
哦 这电池没法用了
Well, the battery's no good.
可他依然试图卖掉
And he still tried to sell it.
还卖了两次
Twice.
贪婪的混蛋
You greedy fuck.
操
Shit.
噢 天啊
Oh God.
操 来吧
Shit, come on.
操
Fuck.
乔尔？
Joel?
玛琳？
Marlene?
你还好吗？
You okay?
还行
Yeah.
艾莉
Ellie.
艾莉！
Ellie!
见鬼！
Oh shit!
没事 我还好 别担心我
No, it's okay. I'll be all right.
你不能干这种蠢事
And you can't be stupid like this.
所以罗伯特为了这人把我们都耍了？
So this is who Robert screwed us over with?
为了波士顿的切·格瓦拉？
The Che Guevara of Boston?
这打的什么破仗
War must be goin' pretty shitty
你居然跟这种人渣买东西
for you to be buying from scumbags like him.
对 大概是这样
Yeah, it kinda has been.
货的质量很差
The merch was bad,
而且 显然他没把“滚蛋”听进去
and he obviously didn't take "fuck off" for an answer.
把我的刀还我
Gimme my knife.
你要卡车电池做什么？
What do you need a car battery for?
别乱动
Don't.
别指她
Not at her.
冲着我好了
Point it at me.
回答你的问题 我有比你更需要电池的理由
And to answer your question, I need it for a better reason than you do.
无意冒犯 可汤米只是一个普通人
No offense, but Tommy's just one man.
了解情况的是我们
It's our business to know things.
“了解情况”
"To know things."
都是你害的 让我亲弟弟跟我闹翻
You're the cause of it. You turned my own brother against me.
好了 乔尔
Okay, Joel.
刚刚的阵仗太大了
That was a lot of gunfire.
FEDRA恐怕在赶来的路上了
FEDRA's gonna be on the way.
我知道
I know.
本来我们今晚要带艾莉离开隔离区
We were gonna move Ellie outta the zone tonight.
但现在这个情况 我们去不了任何地方 至少短期内不行
But we won't make it anywhere like this. Not for a while anyway.
所以 我现在想的是 这个任务可以交给你们
So now I'm thinkin', you're gonna do it.
- 别扯淡 - 我才不要和他们走！
-The hell we are. -I'm not goin' with them!
我可以带她走
-Let me take her. -Tess, we don't have time for this.
泰丝 我们没时间管这码事
Tess, we don't have time for this.
你们没时间？
You don't have time?
- 这女孩是谁？ - 对你们来说 她就是个货物
-Who is she? -To you? She's cargo.
我们不做走私人的生意 抱歉
We don't smuggle people. Sorry.
让我来
I can do it.
金 他妈的你脑袋上已经少了只耳朵了
Kim, you don't have a fuckin' ear on your fuckin' head.
你能不能听我说？
Could you please?
有一只火萤小队在老州议会大厦等着她
There's a team of Fireflies waiting for her at the old State House.
我知道外边有什么
I know what's out there.
就是因为这个 我们才要全员出动
We were going with an entire squadron for that very reason.
可我现在没有卡车 也没有人手
But now I don't have a truck, I don't have a squadron,
FEDRA一眨眼就要到了
FEDRA's five minutes away.
我现在只有你
What I do have is you.
我知道你俩擅长做什么
And I know what you're both capable of.
好事坏事就不论了
For better or worse.
他们能做什么？
What are they capable of?
你把她安全带到地方 他们会提供你想要的东西
You get her there safely, and they'll give you what you need.
不仅仅是电池 全套都有
Not just a battery. The whole thing.
加满油的卡车 枪 补给 全部都有
Fueled-up truck, guns, supplies, all of it.
我发誓
I swear.
臭傻逼！
Asshole!
你相信她？
You trust her?
不 我也不相信 但她似乎在孤注一掷
No, me neither, but she seems desperate.
火萤的车通常是用FEDRA的改装的
Firefly vehicle usually means repurposed FEDRA stuff.
有这么一辆车 我们或许更容易找到汤米
So better-than-decent chance makin' it to Tommy in one of those.
一旦我们把这个孩子交到他们手上——
The second we hand that kid over--
你俩好好谈着 但别忘了我的血还在往外淌
Y'all talk it through, but please remember that I'm bleeding out.
好 我们的条件是这样的
Okay. Here's the deal.
我们把她带到老州议会大厦并交给你的手下
We'll get her to your crew at the State House.
交人之前 他们先把我们要的东西给我们
But before we hand her over, they give us everything that we want.
他们不干 我们就当场杀了她
If not, we kill her, there and then.
成交
Deal.
啥？这就定了？
Really? That fast?
你才是最重要的
You are all that matters.
我们的人不会拿你的生命冒险
My team will not jeopardize that.
记得我跟你说的吗？
Remember what I told you?
快去拿上你的背包
Now go get your backpack.
赶紧 艾莉
Now, Ellie.
走吧
Let's go.
乔尔
Joel,
别他妈搞砸了
don't fuck this up.
拜托你
Please.
给我们一分钟 行不？
Give us a minute, all right?
我操？！
What the fuck?!
你有什么计划？
So, what's the plan?
我们基本上没得选
There's not a lot of options.
有条近路 还有就是那条远路
There's the short way or the long way.
近路实在是……
The short way is pretty much...
只能走远路了
That leaves the long way.
情况看起来很糟 我们得好好想想
Things look bad, we'll come up with something.
咱们不着急 先去比尔和弗兰克家
We'll have to drop, head to Bill and Frank's.
准备好任何可能用得上的物资
Stock up on anything we may need.
《公告牌》
畅销金曲
我们天黑后动身 现在你看着这孩子
We leave after dark. Stay with the kid.
等等 为什么我要—— 泰丝
Wait. Why do I have to-- Tess.
60 - 没货
70 - 新货
80 - X
那 比尔和弗兰克是谁？
So, who's Bill and Frank?
那个收音机收的是走私的暗号 对吗？
The radio's a smuggling code, right?
60年代的歌曲 没有任何新货
'60s song, they don't have anything new,
70年代的 新货到了
'70s, they got new stuff.
80年代的是什么意思？
What's '80s?
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
打发时间
Killin' time.
好吧 那么我该做什么？
Well, what am I supposed to do?
我相信你自己会找到答案的
I'm sure you'll figure that out.
你的表坏了
Your watch is broken.
你睡着的时候一直在说梦话
You mumble in your sleep.
我从没去过隔离墙的另一边
I've never been on the other side of the Wall.
你看 那里好暗
Look how dark it is.
你们经常去那边吗？
You guys go out there a lot?
算是吧
I guess.
上次是什么时候？
When was the last time?
或许有一年了 有什么关系吗？
Maybe a year. What's it matter?
但你知道往哪儿走
But you know where to go.
所以我们会没事的
So we're gonna be okay.
对
Yeah.
你是怎么回事？
So what's the deal with you anyway?
你是什么大佬的女儿还是怎么地？
You some kinda bigwig's daughter or somethin'?
算是吧
Something like that.
对了 你睡着的时候收音机响了
The radio came on when you were sleeping.
什么？
What?
放的是什么歌？
What was the song?
歌一直在唱 大概是什么
He kept sayin', like,
“在你走之前 记得叫醒我”
"Wake me up before you go-go"?
操
Shit.
我懂了
Gotcha.
80年代意思是有麻烦
'80s means trouble.
Wham!《Wake Me Up Before You Go-Go》首次发表于1984年
密码破解
Code broken.
听着——
Listen--
兰开斯特街下方的地洞出口似乎比较安全
The spot under Lancaster looks good.
你包里有外套吗？
You got a jacket in your pack?
有
Yeah.
行 拿出来穿上 到点出发了
Okay, get it. It's time to go.
……宵禁令 对抗感染和叛乱
...mandatory curfew to fight infection and insurrection.
遵守宵禁令
Observe mandatory curfew
对抗感染和叛乱
to fight infection and insurrection.
欢迎
我操 我真的到墙外了
Holy shit. I'm actually outside.
天呐
Jesus Christ.
操
Shit.
好了 我们要绕过缓冲区左侧
Okay, we're gonna take the left edge around the buffer zone.
你跟着我 按我说的做
You stay close and you follow my lead.
好 好 没问题
Yeah. Yeah, of course.
走吧
Let's go.
搞什么？
What the hell?
嘿 嘿 别 别 别动 站住
Hey, hey! Don't, don't, don't move.
站住
Don't move!
你他妈是在逗我
You gotta be shittin' me.
行吧 咱们来谈谈
Okay, let's talk this out.
转过去
Turn around.
等等——
Hold on--
你他妈的给我跪下
Get on your fuckin' knees.
他妈的给我跪下！
Get on your fuckin' knees!
- 稍等—— - 老兄 我他妈是怎么跟你说的？
-Now hold on-- -What did I fuckin' tell you, man?
我说你他妈应该待在家里
I said stay the fuck home.
给我跪下！
Get on your knees!
先跪下 先跪下
Just get on your knees, just get on your knees.
听我说 你放了我们这一马
Listen, you let us do this run,
我们拿到卡以后跟你分
we'll split the cards with you.
- 真的吗？ - 没错
-Will you? -Yeah.
那我太可幸运了
I'm so blessed.
把手放在头上 眼睛往前看
Hands on your head. Eyes forward.
手放头上！
Hands on your head!
拜托 你是认真的？
Really, man?
没错 这次我们按规矩来
Yep. We're doin' this by the book.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
好吧 那你拿四分之三怎么样？
All right. What about three-quarters?
未经许可出隔离区
Unauthorized exit.
他们会把你们吊死
They'll hang you for that.
行了吧 这趟生意 配给卡全归你
Fine. Everythin' off of this run,
药片给你一半
and half off on all of the pills.
给我一半？
Half off?
我要全部
All off.
我冒着失业风险 才换一半药片 你他妈脑——
Risk my job for half off. Outta your fuckin' mind--
艾莉 艾莉！
Ellie, Ellie!
艾莉 搞什么——
Ellie, what the--
操你妈的贱人！
Fuckin' bitch!
操！
Fuck!
你他妈给我让开！
Get out of the fuckin' way!
这个问题我们可以解决
We can fix this.
滚开
Move.
不 不！不 我没生病！
No, no! No, I'm not sick!
-  乔尔！乔尔 乔尔！ - 我没病！我没病！
-Joel! Joel, Joel! -I am not sick! I'm not sick!
看！看！这已经三周了
Look! Look! This is three weeks old.
没人能撑过一天！
Nobody lasts more than a day!
这难道看着像仅有一天吗？
Does this look a day old to you?
要不然你们早就把我杀了！
You would've killed me!
我他妈是该杀了你！
I should fucking kill you!
什么时候发生的？
When did it happen?
那不重要！你得相信我！
It doesn't matter! You have to trust me!
再不跑的话 他们就要抓住我们了！
They're gonna catch us if we don't run!
乔尔 我们得走了 要走了 乔尔！
Joel, we gotta move. We gotta move, Joel!
乔尔！
Joel!
FEDRA警告
生物污染区域
请勿继续前进
片尾曲：Depeche Mode《Never Let Me Down Again》，发表于1987年
关注衣柜字幕组
小红书 微信公众号 西瓜视频@衣柜军团
微博 B站@衣柜军团发声筒
译制人员
北落微博@北落_于百九 B站@北落yubekyu
疾火微博@疾火_凡庸之火将把所有高贵屠戮 B站@尘蕊蝶